Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Zabi family seeks to impose dictatorship
over all of humanity...
...ruling from the Principality of Zeon...
...a gigantic space city-state
floating beyond the moon.
The leader of the Zabi family,
Gihren Zabi...
...waged war against the Earth Federation...
...in order to make all of humanity
kneel before him.
After evading a Zeon attack...
...the White Base escaped from
the space city Side 7...
...and landed on Earth.
However, there was to be no brief rest
for the young crew.
For Amuro, burdened by his parting
from his mother...
...it seemed that his troubles only increased.
Time, Be Still
Here's wishing victory
to the Principality of Zeon!
- Hey, this is boring!
- Get off the stage...!
How long is this going to go on?!
Beat it!
I'd rather have one more bullet
than you bugging me.
Giyal!
No point in getting mad at the pigeon!
I'm stuck in this border zone, polishing Zakus!
Of course I'm angry!
Never mind that, come on down.
I have something to talk about.
All right.
What is it?
Isn't the recreation corps visiting?
It's boring with just a bunch of guys.
You mean, the Federation's mobile suits
are in action around here?
Yeah. Sol's a comm officer reporting directly
to the commander and I heard it from him.
Then... Is our squad heading out?
Idiot. They wouldn't send us.
We're just a patrol squad.
And given how cautious the boss is...
He's not going to start anything.
And?
We're thinking of taking on those mobile suits
just with us new guys.
M-Mobile suits?!
How many do we have to deal with?!
As long as we're doing it on our own...
...the boss says we can try
beating them if we like.
If it goes well, they'll send us home.
Back to nice, clean, bug-free Zeon.
Yeah, but...
But there's only my one Zaku in this squad.
What are you guys going to do?
Tell him the plan, Sol.
They only have one mobile suit.
And it was made in a rush, too.
Is that so...
The engine maintenance will be
completed by dawn.
No need to worry.
So? What did you want to ask me?
We're not part of the regular forces.
So, why are you re-supplying us
and making repairs for us?
The Federation will not
abandon the White Base...
...and they do intend to send you a superior officer.
However, there's a big offensive
being planned in Europe.
Currently, the Federation
doesn't have the luxury of sending...
...relief personnel to a unit like yours
which is holding its own in battle.
Is it that bad?
Zeon is in the same situation.
Besides, the White Base's main mission
is data collection at the moment.
Data collection?
That's right.
Amateurs tend to devise more
interesting tactics than pros.
We collect those tactics
from the computers' memory banks.
So, you ignore us on purpose
to use as guinea pigs.
You don't like being a guinea pig,
Ensign Bright?
I haven't received any such orders.
Ensign? Me?
Yes. That's what General Revil said.
I'm sure you'll be notified soon.
They sure like to jerk us around.
If it wasn't for General Revil,
you would've been executed long ago.
E-Executed?!
Yes.
Amuro, what is it?
N-Nothing.
You're supposed to be asleep right now.
Yes, sir.
Young man.
It's just like Mr. Bright says.
Sleep is part of a pilot's job, too.
Yes, ma'am.
I'll be more careful.
What a guy.
Is it such a crime to have taken control
of the White Base and Gundam?
Up until now, anyway...
...Ensign Bright Noa.
Where have you been?
The toilet.
The toilet's that way.
Well, whatever.
What is it?
Nothing.
Come with me, Haro.
What's her problem?
Amuro, have you had your meal already?
Amuro! Have you had your meal?
N-No, not yet.
We're going to breach
the Zeon patrol network, got that?
Have the Gundam ready on standby.
Y-Yes, sir!
Mr. Bright. This is the escape route
of Matilda's craft.
And this is the White Base.
Both routes are clear.
Will they let us escape?
That depends on Zeon.
I saw a flash of light ahead to the left.
The Minovsky particles are dense.
We can't identify it.
I'll send out a signal flare.
That patrol isn't listed on the schedule.
No response to the flare.
Yes, ma'am.
Take us lower.
We'll escape at combat speed.
Prepare anti-aircraft guns.
It's a Medea transport.
It's flying at maximum combat speed.
That means it's not carrying any cargo.
It must have unloaded the cargo
somewhere near here.
Yes. Could it be related to the Trojan Horse
that Chief Cuaran was talking about?
It's possible. Send out a flare!
Right.
Help get the Zaku ready!
Yes, sir!
Tell the boss we're moving out.
If I launch an attack...
...the enemy will send out
their mobile suit too!
All right? Be sure to tell Cuaran!
Yes, Petty Officer!
Cuaran, don't be late.
Chief Cuaran!
Hey!
Sol, hurry up!
When the mobile suit comes out,
we follow the plan we discussed last night.
Don't forget that we get to go home
if this is a success!
Sol! Ready?
Yes, Chief!
Such a racket, so early in the morning!
That Cuaran guy is always like this.
There it is. The Medea transport.
Return fire at 1 o'clock.
And descent.
That style of attack can only be a Zaku.
Skim over the enemy.
Pretty bold for a big target.
Where is it?
If those Lugguns were covering me, I...
A direct hit to the container!
No matter! Just keep going!
Laser reading... The Medea's in combat!
Ms. Matilda?
The Medea's been snared by a Zeon patrol.
The White Base will provide support.
Mr. Bright! I'll go in the Gundam!
The White Base's supply work
Isn't finished yet, right?
What? That's right, but...
You want to do it?
Yes, sir! I'll launch!
Is that it?
I hope nothing's happened to Ms. Matilda.
The Federation's mobile suit!
It's the Gundam.
He didn't have to come.
Ma'am?
Let's accept the Gundam's kindness
and escape.
Yes, ma'am!
Stay safe, Ms. Matilda.
Don't pursue it too far, Amuro.
Did I get him?!
What's that sound?
T-They are unprotected!
Facing the Gundam with machine guns...
What kind of attack are they planning?
What's wrong?! Why am I shaking?!
I won't let you get away!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
It's your fault for coming out!
Hide under the trees!
You'll get hit from above!
Where are they?!
I'll get you!
What are those? What are they planning?!
Get the weak spots on the armor!
Amuro! Answer me! Amuro!
Did you destroy the Zaku?
Amuro! Can you answer me?!
The enemy ship is here! Retreat and aim
at the bombs on the mobile suit!
Let's go!
Lousy pilot!
All we have to do is hit one of
the bombs we attached, and it's toast.
Why, you...!
Don't underestimate me!
Don't you dare take me for a fool! I'm...!
My shield...!
It's exploded?!
So that's it!
They were planting bombs on the Gundam.
And they're going to...!
I-Is this one of them!
How many did they plant on me?!
Amuro, what's wrong?!
They've planted bombs all over the Gundam!
This isn't a good spot, so...
I'll move to the meadow up ahead and check.
Roger.
Get Omur!
He knows all about bombs!
I can't believe we have to wait 30 minutes
for our bomb timers to go off!
Don't be that way. I never thought
we'd be able to plant them so easily.
Do you think those guys
can save the mobile suit?
If it turns out like this,
I really wish we had remote control bombs.
It would be KABOOM by now.
Yeah, a patrol squad like us
never gets the good stuff.
But can they remove
the bombs in 30 minutes?
There's five left, right?
After the one that blew up?
Should be a show.
I'm not really sure.
I can definitely say that
the timer on this bomb is functioning.
Amuro, can you tell anything
from the x-ray?
Well, all I can tell is...
This thin wire should work like a time fuse...
That's about it.
In other words, if we try to tear off
the plastic explosive from the magnet...
...it'll explode, right, Mr. Omur?
Yeah, that's right.
We've got no choice but to take them off.
All right, I'll do it.
B-But this is my responsibility!
Please stand back, both of you!
There could be no time left at all.
I'll get started on it.
It looks like the pilot's removing the bombs.
If they have any common sense...
...they should know the bombs will explode.
And they're removing them anyway?!
There's only...
...12 minutes left.
Is he serious?!
He's removed the second bomb!
Not bad, for a Federation pilot!
Is he on the third?
Looks like they've got the crane up.
8 minutes left. Will he make it?
Mr. Bright!
Why aren't we all helping him?!
If we all help, it'll be done quicker.
They might explode any second.
In order to minimize the casualties...
...Amuro's the only one who can do it.
But that's so...!
Fraw Bow!
Ms. Mirai, you're a hypocrite too!
You're a coward!
You can say whatever you want.
Restraining yourself is also brave.
We can't let you sacrifice yourself
along with Amuro.
It should be the other way around!
Amuro's a pilot!
I'll do it instead!
Fraw Bow, could you do
a better job than Amuro?
Ms. Mirai...
...you're cruel...!
He's working hard.
If these explode now...
...that's it for Gundam, and for me...
There's one or two left, right?
Should be.
He's persistent.
What kind of guy is he?
They must have noticed the timers by now.
If he's keeping at it despite that,
he's got to be pretty brave.
Pretty brave, huh?
It's taking a lot of time.
He's not coming out.
Let me see!
He's around the back, right?
Yes.
It's just about time.
Damn!
Amuro!
It's no use! Amuro!
All right. If it's just raising a leg or arm...
Take over here!
All of you, stay on the White Base!
What?!
All right! That's enough!
1 minute, 20 seconds.
Can they do it in time?
Amuro! Hurry! It's taken too long!
Okay!
Please go ahead!
All right! We're going 1 kilometer out!
Damn. They removed them all?
Another 18 seconds.
Looks like we won't be going home.
I guess we're not the only ones
risking our lives.
Hey! I wonder what the fool
who removed the bombs is like!
More, please.
Sure!
Oh? There's a car coming.
What?
It's a civilian truck.
No, a station wagon.
That's strange. In a place like this?
Hey, this is unusual!
Is this a Zeon mobile suit?
I don't think so...
Oh my...
Who are you people? Where are you from?
We're just some young guys
from around here.
This is a Federation mobile suit, isn't it?
Is the guy in the white there
perhaps the mobile suit pilot?
What's wrong?
Did you hurt yourself, Mr. Pilot?
Don't look so angry, Mr. Pilot.
Keep up the good fight, soldier!
See ya!
Lucky guys...
People who live on Earth are so lucky.
So carefree.
Those were the ones who planted the bombs.
Yes, it seems that way.
Doan is a brave Zeon veteran who has been molded by the dreadful war.
Amuro hates having to fight a man who only wants to protect war orphans.
Doan's emotions leave a strong impression on him.
Mobile Suit Gundam.
Next time, "Cucuruz Doan's Island."
Next Time
Cucuruz Doan's Island
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...